<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2023-12-07T06:18:46+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Harvinder Atwal</title><subtitle>A man after a dream, after mystery but ultimately just after fun.</subtitle><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Eurotrip</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/eurotrip/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eurotrip" /><published>2022-08-01T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/eurotrip</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/eurotrip/">&lt;p&gt;2 and a half years later we are now on our euro trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test publish&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><summary type="html">2 and a half years later we are now on our euro trip.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hamper Extravaganza</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/hamper-extravaganza/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hamper Extravaganza" /><published>2020-12-18T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-12-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/hamper-extravaganza</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/hamper-extravaganza/">&lt;p&gt;This is a big one, like multiple times too big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;degusta-box.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up let’s start with the classic degusta box&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pipers-crisps&quot;&gt;Pipers crisps&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - The cheesy one was nicely cheesy. The thyme and rosemary was rather different, good for a small portion but would eat too many of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;odysea-aubergine-meze-dip&quot;&gt;Odysea Aubergine Meze Dip&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;leon-aioli-vegan&quot;&gt;Leon Aioli vegan&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Despite the vegan, nice taste and good consistency. The jar is a bit tall and getting the last stuff out is tricky but worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;brave-roasted-chickpeas&quot;&gt;Brave Roasted Chickpeas&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Nice and crunchy, good taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;dash-water&quot;&gt;Dash Water&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cocoa-caramel-peanuts&quot;&gt;Cocoa caramel peanuts&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;club-tropica-ipa&quot;&gt;CLUB Tropica IPA&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great IPA, I’ve added to my beer app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;good-earth-tea&quot;&gt;Good Earth Tea&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - not tried yet, too much other tea at home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;peters-yard-sourdough-bites&quot;&gt;Peter’s Yard Sourdough Bites&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - the Sourdough taste was good but a bit too much on the salty side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nexba-pineapple-soft&quot;&gt;Nexba Pineapple soft&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Was alright. Could have it again, would be a good summer drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;capsicana-cooking-paste&quot;&gt;Capsicana cooking paste&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - We made it with chicken and it was juicy, fruity and spicy at the same time. Would recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;tonys-chocolonely&quot;&gt;Tony’s Chocolonely&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - rather nice and rich taste. I only had a bite but it was a good one.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html">This is a big one, like multiple times too big.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">November box</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/november-box/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="November box" /><published>2020-11-18T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-11-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/november-box</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/november-box/">&lt;p&gt;A surprisingly warm november&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;november-box.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;brioche-baguettes&quot;&gt;Brioche Baguettes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - We made them into oven baguettes and they were surprisingly tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;kitkat-christmas&quot;&gt;Kitkat Christmas&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - There was one big one and a bag with much smaller ones. The big ones was a good portion, the smaller one, same taste but really tiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;wolf-wine&quot;&gt;Wolf Wine&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Cute little bottles, average taste of chardonnay and cabernet, as far as my uncultured pallet can judge this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;hot-chocolate&quot;&gt;Hot chocolate&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvy - I think I remember having this but it seems to be just all the other instant hot chocoate out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;protein-bars&quot;&gt;Protein bars&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Nice and nutty without getting too dry and crumbly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;stroop-waffles&quot;&gt;Stroop waffles&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Stroop waffles can’t be bad! EVER!
Harvy - Agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;advent-tea&quot;&gt;Advent Tea&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Threw it out after many months and several tries as they were all super fruity and weird. Just not my cup of tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;lindt&quot;&gt;Lindt&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Rather delicious, both the mint and the orange. 
Harvy - Had them before, so nothing surprising here. Still very good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;orange-and-cranberry-jaffa-cakes&quot;&gt;Orange and Cranberry Jaffa cakes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Quite nice and juicy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;dijon-mustard&quot;&gt;Dijon Mustard&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - It’s mustard. Nicely strong but we had already mustard at home, and how many open mustard jars do you really need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;coriander-and-basil-pesto&quot;&gt;Coriander and basil pesto&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Not tested it yet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html">A surprisingly warm november</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cozy October box</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/october-box/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cozy October box" /><published>2020-10-18T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-10-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/october-box</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/october-box/">&lt;p&gt;As the summer draws to a close, some cozy treats for october.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;october-box.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;yes-plant-protein-bar&quot;&gt;YES. Plant protein bar&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly tasty and crunchy. Would buy again. Had the almond version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;maltesers-instant-hot-chocolate&quot;&gt;Maltesers Instant Hot Chocolate&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hot chocolate, what’s not to love. I ignored their recommendation of using water and it was still good. But I prefer my hot chocolate powder from Lidl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;reeses-peanut-butter-minis&quot;&gt;Reese’s Peanut Butter Minis&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too good. We devoured them in under 20 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;flapjack&quot;&gt;Flapjack&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Good for a lazy snack. But it’s bigger than one thinks, so not for mini-peckish moments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;chocolate-crepes&quot;&gt;Chocolate crepes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - A bit dry and tasteless. Warm they were definitely better but still not great&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;costa-coffee&quot;&gt;Costa Coffee&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Pretty much like millicano, I suspect you can’t improve on nearly-instant coffee anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cashew-and-oat-cookie&quot;&gt;Cashew and Oat Cookie&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Great little cookiie, wish it was bigger but then it’s good portion control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pretzels&quot;&gt;Pretzels&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;attack-a-snak&quot;&gt;Attack a Snak&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;kitkat-senses&quot;&gt;Kitkat senses&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;brioche-burger-buns&quot;&gt;Brioche Burger Buns&lt;/h5&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html">As the summer draws to a close, some cozy treats for october.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Simmering September box</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/simmering-september-box/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simmering September box" /><published>2020-09-18T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-09-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/simmering-september-box</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/simmering-september-box/">&lt;p&gt;September is here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;simmering-september-box.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;hartleys-jelly-pot&quot;&gt;Hartley’s Jelly Pot&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - “There is always room for Jello” and Bill Murray was right. Nice jello, like all jello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey - I don’t think I had this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mc-vitiess&quot;&gt;Mc Vities’s&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally not a fan of orange flavoured cookies but these were nice. Good mix of crunchiness, gooiness and chocolate taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey - Tina have you been eating all these? Pretty sure I didn’t have this either. /whispers I did it was great. Slightly chewy but the taste and texture made up for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;emily-veg-thins&quot;&gt;Emily Veg Thins&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting alternatives for crisps, crunchy and nice tastes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey - I stayed away from these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;peters-yard-original-sourdough-crispbread&quot;&gt;Peter’s Yard Original Sourdough Crispbread&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice take on the cracker, good with smelly cheese and a drop of sour marmalade. Yum yum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;fulfil-chocolate-hazelnut-whip-bar&quot;&gt;FULFIL Chocolate Hazelnut Whip Bar&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Nice and smooth, very indulgent and not too bad on the calorie count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Agree very smooth and just the right mix of textures and flavours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;whitworths-chocolate-biscuit--hazelnut-treat-mix&quot;&gt;Whitworths Chocolate Biscuit &amp;amp; Hazelnut Treat Mix&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - The bits and pieces were not bad, but the mix of raisins and nuts and chocolate freaks me out. I want to know if it is crispy, sweet or gooey and salty before i bite on it, even if I chuck them down without looking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Really like the mix of different but complimentary snacks. Just shove a load in your mouth and let it all mix up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;thatchers-cloudy-lemon-cider&quot;&gt;Thatchers Cloudy Lemon Cider&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Surprisingly a refreshing drink that’s good for the summer days/nights. Reminds me of a bottled &lt;a href=&quot;https://germanfoods.org/recipes/radler/&quot;&gt;radler from germany&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;chicken-yakisoba&quot;&gt;Chicken Yakisoba&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;more-maple-syrup-this-time-mini&quot;&gt;More Maple syrup, this time mini&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did we even use this? It’s probably just disappeared&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;vegetable-barley-soup&quot;&gt;Vegetable Barley soup&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;lucozade&quot;&gt;Lucozade&lt;/h5&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html">September is here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hot Hot August Box</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/hot-hot-august-box/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hot Hot August Box" /><published>2020-08-18T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-08-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/hot-hot-august-box</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/hot-hot-august-box/">&lt;p&gt;The August Box arrived and we were not there to pick up. Shout out to Alan who put in our house as we were away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;hot-hot-august-spread.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvy&quot;&gt;Harvy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling a bit lighter than other boxes, so was just expecting no drinks but suprise! Iced coffee. To be honest I’m not that excited with this one, between the chai tea and chai breakfast blend going to the puds sweets, there’s not much inspiration here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;swizzels-puds&quot;&gt;Swizzels Puds&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - I didn’t feel that these wanted production, I’ve had a lot of chewy streets and especially refreshers which this comes very close to. The different flavours were a mixed bag. Sticky toffee I think didn’t work out well and the rest were palatable. Probably won’t buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - Imagine a colourful blob made almost entirely of sugar with an artificial hint of a flavour of some popular desserts. There you go. You never get all of the slowly melting stuff out of your teeth again. But it is so sweet, do you really want to? (Not recommended by 100/10 dentists)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;boundless&quot;&gt;Boundless&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - The only thing I remember from this is the hit of chilli after you finish the nuts. I’m not sure why this is a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;simpleas&quot;&gt;Simpleas&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Tina didn’t want it as it had vinegar. The pea taste for me was just overpowered by the salt and vineger and texture was just like eating mush. Not a fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;capsicana---cooking-paste&quot;&gt;Capsicana - cooking paste&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - We tried a variety of the added recipe and it was rather nice. A different taste to the usual cooking pastes. Not too spicy and tastes almost naturally. Intense smell during cooking. Would buy again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - I only tasted the end result but I was impressed, would also buy and then make Tina cook with again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;sunny-fruit-mix-up&quot;&gt;Sunny fruit mix up&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No comments, I guess it was just meh then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pickup&quot;&gt;Pickup&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - I know them from other countries, and they are a nice snack. Had the hazelnut one which had soft chocolate in the middle. Looking forward to the white and milk chocolate versions too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;iced-coffee&quot;&gt;Iced Coffee&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cold-infused-tea&quot;&gt;Cold Infused “Tea”&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;yet-another-chai-latte&quot;&gt;Yet another Chai Latte&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;protein-bar&quot;&gt;Protein Bar&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;porridge&quot;&gt;Porridge&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tina - Good but how bad can porridge be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;start-me-chia&quot;&gt;Start me Chia&lt;/h5&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html">The August Box arrived and we were not there to pick up. Shout out to Alan who put in our house as we were away.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer July box</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/summer-july-box/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer July box" /><published>2020-07-18T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/summer-july-box</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/summer-july-box/">&lt;p&gt;The July Box arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;summer-july-spread.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nesquik&quot;&gt;Nesquik&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - 5 stars for effort, as it doesn’t have artificial sweetener, less sugar and even the package is paper based and can be recycled. We compared it with a chocolate powder we already had at home, and it unfortunately didn’t do well in comparison. Not bad, but not great either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nativa&quot;&gt;Nativa&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - Tested this in a drink for sweetening. I just wished the package would have a warning, that it is more potent than sugar. Would have used less than a full teaspoon. So sparsely dosed it does the job with sweetening your drinks and foods. They say you can use it for baking as well. While that is great news, it seems very experimental without a conversion ratio. Wouldn’t mind a sweet cake without sugar, but could end up with way too much or not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;skinny-food-sauces&quot;&gt;Skinny food sauces&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - We got 4 sachets of sauces and sirups from this company. I tried the sirup for a Latte but it was hardly detectable in sweetness or flavour. Great that is has hardly any calories, but without any flavour not the best trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - It’s all horrible, don’t buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;golden-creek-maple-syrup&quot;&gt;Golden Creek (Maple syrup)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - For people who can’t live without syrup on their pancakes definitely a good option. Sticky and sweet as advertised. The non-maple part is dominating, making it a bit too sweet for my taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - I don’t normally buy syrup but was pretty nice on pancake, which I think is the only thing they can be used for? I can’t remember what normal syrup tastes like, so can’t compare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;premier-protein-chocolate-brownie-flavoured-protein-bar&quot;&gt;Premier Protein (chocolate brownie flavoured protein bar)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - Tastes like it looks, sweet, dense and good flavour of chocolate. Good portion for when you are hungry but too busy or too lazy to actually make yourself a sandwich. Good after gym or outdoor snack. Available only at ocado and WHSmith travel, so won’t see any of them for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;wunda-pea-drink&quot;&gt;Wunda (pea drink)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - If you are used to Oat and Almond drinks, this is just as good or bad, depending on what your experience was with Oat and Almond drinks. With 1.99 per litre definitely on the pricey side even compared to other plant based milk replacements. 
Harvy - I already dislike oatly and this is probably worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;bebeto-sugar-candy-box&quot;&gt;Bebeto (sugar candy box)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - Like all sugary candy which comes in small portions in large boxes, one easily gets hooked and keeps on eating without reason. The mix of sour, sugar and the refreshing artificial flavours of the different items make it fun. Unfortunately the least fun item makes up 50% of the whole box. Was fun to eat, but probably would buy again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Great little sugar box but just too much of the watermelon sweet, maybe a few more different flavours. Probably would get it at the right price but pretty sure supermarket do own label versions and I don’t buy those sooooo….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;plant-pops-popped-lotus-seeds&quot;&gt;Plant pops (popped Lotus seeds)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tina - I heard about lotus seeds and was very excited about this. But once they are popped like sweetcorn kernels and flavoured with peanut, it’s hard to find an original taste. Definitely a fun snack and good alternative for popcorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pravha&quot;&gt;Pravha&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Surpisingly refreshing pilsner, fairly light as well and filled up my 1 litre jug quite nicely. I could be seen drinking the bigger bottles for a nice summer beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;chai-latte&quot;&gt;Chai Latte&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - Finally got around to this a few months later. Tasted pretty much like most chai lattes. I’m used to the starbucks supermarket versions and it was pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;manilife&quot;&gt;Manilife&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy - It’s just peanut butter but barely enough to cover toast. What was the USP here?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html">The July Box arrived.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yummy yummy June box</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/yummy-yummy-june-box/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yummy yummy June box" /><published>2020-06-12T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-06-12T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/yummy-yummy-june-box</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/yummy-yummy-june-box/">&lt;p&gt;The June Box arrived and was looking good at first sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;yummy-yummy-june-spread.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tina&quot;&gt;Tina&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big bottle of Gin Fizz was dominating in the box, just a shame it was pink. Nevertheless, looking forward to taste it, after cooling it of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also several snack items, which waited for that afternoon motivation plunge to be devoured - Chickpea puffs, fruit jellies, roasted corn and sweet cereal and marshmallow bars. There was also another bottle of salad dressing, which - together with the two from last month - mean, we better start eating salads. We will have to fight the slugs in the veg-bed more rigorously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvy&quot;&gt;Harvy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things have caught my eye but there’s also a few that I’m not bothered about (yet another salad dressing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s “Attack a Snak” which reminds me of lunchables, they were a desperation food but would probably have it again, so interested to see how these turn out.
I’m looking forward to Baru (?) because who doesn’t like chocolate marshmallow in a bar. Noisy snacks looks intreg they boast they use double the flavouring of other snacks. Is that a good thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;superfruit-jellies&quot;&gt;Superfruit Jellies&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overwhelming smell to the point of artificial. The choice of flavours was :shaky hands but not trump: It just seemed to break up in your mouth but not really melt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;baru-chocolate-marshmallow-bar&quot;&gt;Baru Chocolate Marshmallow Bar&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks like expected for a Marshmallow chocolate bar, nice and soft. A little too sweet for the generous size, but marshmallow lovers will probably like it. It was supposed to be Chai Latte flavour, but there wasn’t much of it, which I actually preferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;le-joli&quot;&gt;Le Joli&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically flavoured sparkling water. Which has never tasted nice… ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;attack-a-snack&quot;&gt;Attack A Snack&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small nachos with some overpowering bbq chipoltle sauce (way too much sugar as well) and not sure why they included the cream sauce as well. Can’t really recommend this, like cinema nachos but worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;noisy-corn&quot;&gt;Noisy corn&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heavily flavoured corn, works pretty well actually. Good little snack but I feel it might too pricey when released&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;ollys-olives&quot;&gt;Olly’s Olives&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure what the product is supposed be here. It’s just olives with garlic and basil. I mean the olives were good but you can find this in different variation from stock supermarket food in the deli section. Snack sized which worked in its favour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;lizis-granola-high-protein-40g&quot;&gt;Lizi’s Granola High Protein (40g)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The miniture package is a harsh reminder of how small a “recommended portion” really is. However, the stuff in my bowl looked promising, nicely brown coloured, suggesting a good roast or the grains. But once you add the milk everthing starts to float. Turns out, most is puffed grains, not much to chew on. Taste was plesant but the overall impression falls behind the high expectantions I got from their cover picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvy thought it needed more sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nine-bar&quot;&gt;Nine Bar&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good meal replacement options for a hectic day or after exercise. Good flavour and the full stomach feeling you get from dense energy bars like this. A bit too much for a light snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;gregorys-tree&quot;&gt;Gregory’s Tree&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially the healthier version of fruit twists? I’m not sure why these exist to be honest. I’m sure the standard full fat version costs less and I think they are supposed to bad for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;hippeas&quot;&gt;Hippeas&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liking the big crunchy pieces. It was vinegar flavour but it wasn’t as overpowering as your normal salt and vinegar snack but would look forward to other flavours. Kinda reminded me of wotsits but less chessy, and I assume it’s more healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvy-1&quot;&gt;Harvy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really liked the marshmellow bar (of course who wouldn’t), I think the unexpected winner here was the noisy corn snack.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html">The June Box arrived and was looking good at first sight.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One crazy estate agent Part 2</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/one-crazy-estate-agent-part-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One crazy estate agent Part 2" /><published>2017-06-08T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/one-crazy-estate-agent-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/one-crazy-estate-agent-part-2/">&lt;p&gt;Weeks later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After changing solictors, as they were not on the approved list for my mortgage provider (Who knew… more red tape!),the estate agent didn’t like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I need a call immediately, I have just called your solicitor for an update and been told that they are no longer acting for you. It would have been polite to call and let me know about this, I will need the details of a new solicitor today.
Please call the office asap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was after I email a few days before to tell them of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anywho. I already had another one lined up. Again dates: Friday 28th April to instruct them to work for us, we got the papers the next and had a read though. We decided that we should go down and hand everything in on the same day. Scheduled that for 9th May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s the estate agent again, the day before my visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve spoken to your solicitors, they have informed me that they are not able to undertake any work on your behalf as they are awaiting the return of your formal instruction letter and payment for search fees. They documents were sent to you on the 2nd of May (last Tuesday).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;They have received the draft contract and all required documents from the vendors solicitor and are aware you are taking a mortgage from Yorkshire Building Society, they said this lender is generally very swift at releasing the mortgage funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am pressing you to move swiftly as the vendor starts his new job on the 5th of June and needs this to be completed by that date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have a date but I was unsure about why she was telling me what my solictor has done for me. I mean thanks for the update but is this supposed to me make me go faster?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say that we are meeting tomorrow to sort out the paperwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Brilliant, thank you for letting me know.
Would the 5th of June as a date for completion work for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I consult as to what to do here. Is this legally binding? I decide to hold off and say I will talk to my solictor as to what dates can be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the estate agent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please let me know if this date is feasible asap – so that I can confirm with the vendor and allow him to book in his removal company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still hold off but never actually reply. She never chased up for that date. I guess it wasn’t important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solictor starts working and then another email from the estate agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dear Mr. Atwal,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have also left a message for your solicitor regarding the email below from the vendors solicitor. As you are aware we are hoping to complete in this sale at the end of next week. If you could chase your solicitor for me that would be very much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What followed was a thread of confusing emails between the solictors. It seemed everything was going to plan and I wasn’t even sure what to ask my solictor. Hmm confusing, it seems that there was a sense of desperation of the vendor which was coming though the estate agent but it was compromising communication between all parties. This process required the upmost clarity between all parties, especially for a first time buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More fun from the estate agent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dear &amp;lt;solicitor&amp;gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The vendors solicitor has come back to me since the last email, she said she has finally received your enquires. She can get these all back to you by Tuesday. Can you prepare your files and arrange for your client to come in and sign the contracts next week please. Ideally we want to complete next Friday. /&lt;vendors solictor=&quot;&quot;&gt; has made me aware that this the pace at which you are working that is unlikely. We are therefore giving you notice that we wish to exchange contracts no later than next Friday and complete the following week as early as possible.&lt;/vendors&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the solictor was not getting happy with this tone from the estate agent. They had never seen this behaviour before and wanted to give us an update to make sure nothing was out of place and discussed different theories like, was this was a new estate agent, maybe they didn’t know how buying a house worked (that theory was shot down, as apparently they had 10 years experience). With an unhappy solicitor and a pushy estate agent can get it get worse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this was happening I was still waiting for a mortgage offer. This was then made apparent to the estate agent. Uh oh.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><summary type="html">Weeks later.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One crazy estate agent Part 1</title><link href="https://harvinderatwal.com/one-crazy-estate-agent/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One crazy estate agent Part 1" /><published>2017-05-10T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2017-05-10T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://harvinderatwal.com/one-crazy-estate-agent</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harvinderatwal.com/one-crazy-estate-agent/">&lt;p&gt;There’s a few moments in your life where you have to deal with someone who just doesn’t have a handle on humanity. 
This is one of those times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me and my girlfriend just got back from a viewing and agreed this is house we could move into. Let’s put an offer in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the phone call with the estate agents, something seemed a bit off. I had offered £10k less then the asking. The estate agent, who just happened to be the MD said if I could offer the asking price she can accept it striaght away. I held off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprise! The next day an offer came in from a potential buyer for the asking price but they didn’t give it away, instead I was offered to do…. something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So what can I do here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well it’s up to you.” I could sense some smirking in the voice but maybe it was me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll get back to you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided it put in the asking price, still dubious but we could accept the cost over a long mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprise! 30 minutes later the vendor accepted our offer… Hmmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timelines are going to be interesting here. It’s the 28th March (Day 1).
An email on the same day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I will now need solicitors details, please let me know if you would like me to recommend some good solicitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok great I think, just send me a list. My response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That’s great!
I don’t have any solicitors lined up, so if you could send me a list that would be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No problem, please speak to these people and let me know who you are working with as soon as you have selected one, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;list of=&quot;&quot; solicitors=&quot;&quot;&gt;
To make life easier I will ask them each to contact you with a quote.
&lt;/list&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wut? Umm thanks for sending my information across. Anyway it’s now Day 2, 9:21 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Good morning,
I just wondered if you have selected a solicitor to work with on this purchase?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explain that from yesterday only one has got back to me and they couldn’t work with my mortgage provider. I will get back once I have made a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:04 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How you getting on? Any progress with speaking to solicitors?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ignore them…. for today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3. Ahh what a nice morning. Oh what’s this? An email from 8:51 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Good morning Harvinder,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As I explained on Tuesday you were selected over the other asking price offer as I was under the impression you could move more quickly on this purchase. The vendor is now telling me that we should take the other offer if we don’t have solicitors on file this morning. Can you please come back to me in the next hour with your choosen firm!  I don’t want to have to terminate the sale so soon, but we will need this to move along swiftly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you soon, if you need my advice please do call the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explain I have now chosen a solictor and give the law firm details. A bit annoyed she is using this mystery buyer to push the sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11 minutes later…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just spoken to &amp;lt;Law firm&amp;gt; and they don’t seem to have a file for you…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give her the case number and suddenly get a flurry of emails from the estate agent with my solictors details which even I didn’t know and an agreement to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then nothing…. for weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Harvinder Atwal</name><email>blog@harvinderatwal.com</email></author><summary type="html">There’s a few moments in your life where you have to deal with someone who just doesn’t have a handle on humanity. This is one of those times.</summary></entry></feed>